{"forumData":[{"question":"hi were there answers for tute 7 part 2 written 1. consider the following user-stories and implement a set of test-cases to match the acceptance criteria thanks.","answers":[{"text":"hi the answers should be available now in the tut/lab 7 section","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi will we have questions that really need to be run in python i mean i know we will be asked on writing some code like pytest class. will these code be run or just look","answers":[{"text":"yes","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"so we have to use python during exam do we need to install pytest in the exam","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"it s pre-installed.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"where is information on the purpose of strategy design pattern","answers":[{"text":"you are expected to know only about the uml of a strategy design pattern and generally what it does. the actual fine details is taught in 2511. for your interest strategy pattern enables selection of algorithms at run time. essentially what happens is there is a behaviour or algorithm class which abstracts multiple types of algorithms ie. sort abstracts quicksort bubblesort yet all the types of sorts are in their own class and implement sort function differently. run-time means that during execution of code we can essentially inject this sorting behaviour by instantiating a sort object one that extends sort class and placing it inside any object which is able to utilise its sorting behaviours. we can treat sorts all the same way because of abstraction sortingalgorithm.sort for example.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"how do we run pytest on cse machines i have installed pytest but when i run pytest -v xxx it says pytest command not found. thank you.","answers":[{"text":"use the virtual environment or try python3 -m pytest.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"composition vs ocp. for the car wash class diagram in the practice test it claims the class job is a composition of class joblist. this means an instance of job should only be instantiated inside the joblist function add_job. however if we were to conform to ocp the job instance should be instantiated outisde this function so we do not need to change the arguments passed into add_job unlike the composition example . i just want some clarification on this and which one would be more correct.","answers":[{"text":"ocp relates to extending behaviour without modifying source code. i would argue that add_job does the exact same thing you are not extending behaviour you are simply adding one more argument to allow it to do what it was intended to do. this could be more of an issue of fragility . i would say that both approaches are perfectly reasonable it would depend if you wanted to enforce composition or not. if you are pedantic enough one could create a parameter class for storing job information to be passed in. this itself could turn into an issue.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi will both unittests and pytest be assessed or just pytest thanks.","answers":[{"text":"only pytest. unittest will not be examined","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi in examined lecture content it says this week 05 - no html 5/css flask python decorators does this mean all these things won't be examined since all other parts are the content which will be examined i'm a bit confused about this line.","answers":[{"text":"you will not be writing html css or flask in the exam.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"is www and web architecture in the exam","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"no you will not be questioned on www http request/response etc.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"so is any of week 5 examinable","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"for quiz 3 the marks in my grades show that i'm still missing a mark due to the adjustment with question 4 i've double checked with the given answers has this been changed in the database and just isn't shown in my grades","answers":[{"text":"yes this will not be reflected on webcms3 it will be internally adjusted on our database as we process the final marks","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"will we have to do any coding in flask for the exam","answers":[{"text":"no please follow the revision guide which under your lecture 13 lecture content.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"can we see the answer to tutorial week10","answers":[{"text":"it is visible now.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"can we please have the answers to quiz 3","answers":[{"text":"it's under week 13' contents of your lectures.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"when will we know quiz 3 marks","answers":[{"text":"hi it should be up by now","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"how to check which of these i was right and wrong thanks","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"so there are no week13 tutes/labs my timetable shows otherwise..","answers":[{"text":"no week 13 tuts/labs as tuts amp labs commenced in week 1 this semester.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi are methods of an object meant to be functions on themselves only or can an object student for example have a method called searchclasses whereby it interacts with object called classesmanager which contains a list of classes. student.searchclasses would perform a search through the list of classes in classesmanager. is this thought process and understanding of methods correct sorry that was a bit much to understand but to try to condense are object methods meant to be independent of other objects so they can exists independently and all their methods work without the existence of other objects thank you","answers":[{"text":"edit to answer your question about method independence when an object is instantiated myobj object this specific instance of the object is unique and differentiated from any other instance you may create. note that the majority of methods defined basically all in this course in the class require an object instance of the class to exist to even use them. they can be referred to instance methods. i can use them calling myobj.method","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"that makes sense thank you","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"methods are typically responsible for attributes of itself or possibly of objects of which it aggregates or composes. from what you are saying wouldn't it make more sense for the classesmanager to have the method which searches through the classes list it holds don't think physically in terms of a student doing it.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"sorry for bothering from what you are saying if students want to see the information of classes this viewing method is better to put under classmanager rather than student right because the classmanager actually holds the information.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"if a student wishes to view all available classes this information is simply pulled from classmanager through a classmanager method like getclasses then displayed via a for-loop which can be done easily on html. if a student wanted to search there simply would be a search method in classmanager to return a list of the relevant classes to display. not always are object methods simply acting upon themselves although they are utilising some data they are already holding at the very least.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"get it thank you very much","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"would you say it's correct to think of methods as 'things done on the object rather than by the object'","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"that wouldn't be a bad way to think about it. although i wouldn't be overly stringent on sticking to mantras or design principles. they are mostly to give you a general idea of good design.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"ok thank you","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi i just found the quiz can be submitted more than once is this designed to be so or it is only me having an unstable internet connection.","answers":[{"text":"not sure if intended but other students have stated they have been able to. edit should only be for this week","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"are we required to program using a certain version of python if so what version thanks","answers":[{"text":"python3 latest version","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thank you","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"for the setup task i already have an account on github and it is a student account so it allows for free private repos. i'm just wondering whether an education account is the same thing as a student account or if an education account includes the pack https //education.github.com/students","answers":[{"text":"hi alex as long as you can use private repos for free it's all good that is all we need it for - no need to apply for the education pack again. hope this helped cheers ian","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"can we submit the report as a number of files that contain each part needed i.e the log book the er model class diagram being in separate files under the 'report' folder or does it have to be in one file in the folder","answers":[{"text":"please merge it into one report pdf if possible.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"how should we submit the final report is there any give command or just push it to github thanks","answers":[{"text":"report folder within master branch. there is no give command only github.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi could you tell me what type of classes from our class diagram do we not include in the er diagram for example we're assuming we don't include classes such as providermanager in the er diagram.","answers":[{"text":"also we're on the same team do inherited entities not need a primary key thanks.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi for the class diagram do we need to include classes that inherit from exception also i'm not too sure what methods that create decorators return e.g. patient_required since i used the lab08 code for login in terms of that.","answers":[{"text":"i'm not a tutor but i dont think exceptions should be in the class diagram as they arent part of the system","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"exceptions are not really part of the business domain. i personally would not model them.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi i am wondering whether all team members need to give the presentation i know all the members should attend to the lab but should all team members give the presentation together","answers":[{"text":"hi zhilin i would highly recommend all team members to actively participate in the project demonstration as this also plays a part in the quality of your presentation.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thanks for your reply","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"pytest all our test cases are done except for flexible partial name searches etc. our search function returns a list of providers how do we use asserts to test what this returns should i make a separate function for this an example of part of our code thanks","answers":[{"text":"hey sai one way you could test your search function is to compare its output with the expected output. since your function returns a list of providers please take a look at list/set comparison methods. i am guessing you have multiple search functions so i agree with you on making a separate function for the comparison.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"just wondering if we need to create test cases for this because according to this we only need to create tests cases for the 3 core user stories https //webcms3.cse.unsw.edu.au/static/uploads/cou...","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"yes test-cases are only needed for the the above user-stories","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"question about test cases just wanna confirm that we only need to create test cases for these 3 user stories https //webcms3.cse.unsw.edu.au/static/uploads/cou...","answers":[{"text":"yup that's right.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi can someone please clarify how to use give to submit","answers":[{"text":"there is no give submission push to final release branch as shown in specs. the name of branch is case sensitive so copy it exactly from specs.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thanks for reply but for final report all uml diagram do we still need to push to final_release branch or some other way to submit","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"please put report inside final_release branch within a folder named 'report'.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"attributeerror 'str' object has no attribute 'login' i'm doing the pytest and occur this error. how can i fix that","answers":[{"text":"hey haonan the error just indicates that self._auth_manager is of type string and not the type it is meant to be. please have a look at where you assigned the value to self._auth_manager.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"doing the final checks of the specification and the code i've come up with a query - pytest for our system we handle the majority of the error checking on the front end and presume all data is sanitised and corrected by the front end so our backend has very little data checking outside of a few functions where appropriate currently we have a full coverage testing of searching and making appointments along with a few minor other functions such as whether or not you can book with x provider and new_referral. - we don't have any tests for managing patient history notes / viewing patient history since all of that is handled by the front end for example on an appointment we store the provider that was part of that appointment along with the patient so we can simply just check if you were the provider that made such appointment and if so then you can edit the notes . i've read previously that in this case we wouldn't have to test the history and just want to confirm this d.","answers":[{"text":"pytests will not be required for front-end validation checks e g. if a required input has not been provided date-formats etc.. however use-cases such as editing patient history would still require to be checked using pytests as these are not mere front-end validation checks and adding notes to an existing patient's history does invoke a back-end function and results in a change to the model in this case the patient's history data.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi i was wondering whether we should remove acceptance criteria related to visuals out of our user stories for example there is a calendar widget because it's hard to implement pytest for these cases. thanks","answers":[{"text":"angela you do not need to remove the acceptance criteria related to front-end validation or view components. these can be verified by customer during end-of-iteration demo i.e uat by customer in this case the tutor . pytests are only required for back-end functionality","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi since previous spec states every provider has a profession what is the profession of specialist","answers":[{"text":"hi william the profession of a specialist is left for you to decide based on what best helps the user the profession could simply be 'specialist' or the field of expertise associated with the specialist. you should be able to support your decision with a clear reason.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"in the spec it says each healthcare provider seen by the patient may request access to able to view/edit the history of the patient to add their specific notes during the consultation with the patient. healthcare providers will not be able to edit the past history recorded by other providers but will only be able to add their own specific notes about the patient s visit. but then in the scenarios it seems as if those who a patient books with automatically get access to the notes who is receiving/approving this request am i missing something here are my two interpretations 1. once the patient books with a provider they automatically can click on the patients history add new notes but cannot change old notes. in this case the request is either a poor choice of words or a request to the server 2. once the patient books with a provider the provider can request to the patient or provider to be able to view previous notes then the patient or provider can click accept of some sort to enable access. another question this example has also confused me healthcare providers in healthcare centres that the patient has not visited must not have access to the patient s history. does this imply that if a user goes to a health provider at health centre x every other provider at health centre x does have a copy of the patients history","answers":[{"text":"hi owen for the first question both will be considered acceptable but i would recommend the first option. as for the second question only the health providers that has/had an appointment with a particular patient may access their appointments history.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi is adding more than one note per appointment required from the spec also is it okay to have a user's userid consist of their password and username combined thanks.","answers":[{"text":"hi angela adding multiple notes per appointment is not required for this project. as for the second part i can see why you might want to use username password as a user-id but using an attribute or set of attributes that is subject to changes is usually not recommended for use as a primary key. additionally having a key that consists of more than 1 attributes is not recommended for complexity amp efficiency issues. in the case like this i advise introducing a separate 'id' attribute whose value is uniquely assigned for each user e.g. increment by 1 for every new user . cheers","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"committing in the last 48 hours. i was under the impression that as long as you don't commit everything is the last 48 hours you will not lose marks but apparently if you commit even something small it will result to lost marks. so is this assignment due monday 10am or saturday 10am","answers":[{"text":"where majority of work is done in last 48 hours. that will be fixed sorry.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"the specification states that the software should also be submitted by give command. what is the command for milestone3 submission cheers","answers":[{"text":"hi di wu we have decided that there is no need for give submissions for the milestone 3. there will be an update announcement soon.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"according to the specs a registered user should be able to update their profile details. do these updates need to reflect across even after the web server is stopped and rerun or should these updated details only persist as long as the web server is kept running","answers":[{"text":"persistence of data is required for this final iteration. you can do so by saving objects to files using pickle then loading them back up on server start.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"there is a 500 server error when trying to access the sample project link is http //cgi.cse.unsw.edu.au/ cs1531/18s2/sample_project/run.cgi/ . can this be fixed or is it being purposefully shut down","answers":[{"text":"would like to know this too.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi i have a question about who can see a patients history. the spec has these two points a provider is granted access to a patient s history only after the patient has made an appointment with the provider. healthcare providers in healthcare centres that the patient has not visited must not have access to the patient s history. does this means that if a patient jack has an appointment with provider ian at centre a provider toby who also works at centre a should not be able to see jacks history if so then isn't the second point redundant since all that matters is that the patient has an appointment with the provider not the centre the provider works at. however if toby can see jacks history the first point is violated since toby doesn't have an appointment with jack. can someone please clarify whether or not toby can see jacks history thanks","answers":[{"text":"providers who have appointments with toby should be the only people who ever have access to the patient toby history. look at the examples.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi i was just wondering whether a provider can only add notes for patients during the consultation and after the consultation the provider cannot edit the patients' notes right like provider feels unhappy for the notes her took during the consultation and she wants to edit it after the consultation.","answers":[{"text":"each healthcare provider seen by the patient may request access to able to view/edit the history of the patient to add their specific notes during the consultation with the patient. healthcare providers will not be able to edit the past history recorded by other providers but will only be able to add their own specific notes about the patient s visit. from specs i'd interpret this as able to edit your own past notes not other providers.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"also can the provider anna view the profiles of her past patients who do not have appointments with anna currently","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi can only providers who are a gp refer a patient to a specialist or can any provider refer a patient to a specialist thanks","answers":[{"text":"general practioners sending referrals to specialists where gp's and specialists are grouped under providers. interpret that how you will.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi i was just wondering if we need to register new users for the 3rd milestone.the spec was vague about this so i'm not sure what to do.","answers":[{"text":"you do not need to register new users as this would require you to implement additional functionality. you are only required to use the set of credentials provided in the csv files","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi looking through the specialist and provider csv files i noticed that gary gmail.com is present in both lists. considering patients can only book appointments with specialists after being referred to by a provider do we treat gary as a provider or a specialist","answers":[{"text":"sorry that must be a mistake. to keep it simple you can continue to treat gary as a provider and not as a specialist.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi right now our group reads from csv files to instantiate providers patients etc. in order to change this to be stored on pickle and use dao classes is dumping the patients providers etc. into a pickle file after reading and then loading enough or should reading from the csv files to instantiate not even happen","answers":[{"text":"the csv files have been provided so that you will not need to build any register user functionality. you simply use the set of users provided to you in the csv files. so one way would be to just read the csv file as a one-off and then use pickle to save and reload the data. you don't need to read the csv each time the app starts as long as the file dumped by pickle exists.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"for the patient history if a provider has access to a certain patients history as they have been visited in the past do they have access to the patient's entire history or only the appointments that were with that particular provider","answers":[{"text":"the provider will have access to the patient's entire history. the objective of the centralised history is provide access to the patient's complete history to all providers that the patient has visited","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"for some of the errors my group has handled them through the implementation of the front end but according to the deliverable document pytests are required to be written for them - does this mean i can ignore those test cases or should i change the way the errors are handled","answers":[{"text":"it is absolutely fine and in fact this is often the case if some validation errors are handled by the front-end. pytests are more about testing the working of back-end software to ensure that it behaves as expected for e.g. you could be testing a search for cases such as case insensitivity partial string match etc.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi with regards to the milestone 3 spec just wanted some clarification for history viewing privileges. here are some scenarios patient jack has an upcoming appointment with provider tony at centre a. provider anna also works at centre a however jack has never seen anna. will anna be able to access jack's history once the appointment is complete does tony still have access to jack's history if so will tony be able to see appointments made and completed after his own with other providers possibly at different centres thank you","answers":[{"text":"laura if provider anna has never seen patient jack then anna will not have access to jack's history. only the providers that tony has seen could be at different centres will be able to access jack's history. of course patient jack always has access to his own complete history.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi i was wondering whether use of sqlalchemy is required for this iteration or is using pickle fine thanks","answers":[{"text":"we have not specified for a specific type of persistence so using pickle is fine.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"can someone please clarify how to use give to submit software and report","answers":[{"text":"hi as noted in the announcement you are only required to use github for submissions","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"if we upload reports to final_release will it count as a late submission of the software will tutors check that we have only submitted documentation after the software due date","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i believe that you can upload your reports to master. just tell your tutor.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"is gary gmail.com suppose to be a specialist and a gp as given in the specialist.csv and provider.csv files and are specialists suppose to have affiliations with healthcentres","answers":[{"text":"hi zaim please ignore the entry with gary gmail.com in the specialist.csv. as for the health centre affiliations you may fill in the details yourself please note that you are also free to add more specialists to the existing csv file e.g. for testing reasons .","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi suppose our team has implemented our html/jinja so only available timeslots and providers can be booked do we still need to write test cases for theoretical invalid input that isn't able to be inputted anyway","answers":[{"text":"hi owen for this assignment no pytest is required for invalid inputs that would be filtered out by your front-end. please refer back to aarthi's answer to another question here for more detail https //webcms3.cse.unsw.edu.au/comp1531/18s2/foru... .","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"with the pytest deliverable. do we have to have all of our tests in a single test.py file or can we have separate test_ .py files as our group currently has about 6-7 files already before this deliverable was announced. just wondering if we need to combine them all into one file as it might get a bit messy","answers":[{"text":"hi jonathan the submission requires a single tests.py to be submitted as you have mentioned. i understand that it may get a bit messy but please adhere to the submission guidelines. you can have them on separate files then merge them into a single file afterwards if you would like to do so .","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"when updating the user stories for the specification changes should i include error handling/testing in the user stories similar to the user stories in the car rental system lab","answers":[{"text":"hey van-roy there is no need to do so you are welcome to do it if you would like to you are only required to write your user stories in the same way as back in iteration 1 user story narrative priority user story points acceptance criteria etc. .","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"been getting this error each time i run pytest or even try to check the current pytest version. what could be wrong","answers":[{"text":"hi ravija could you please try using pip3 for python v3 instead of pip v2","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi i'm wondering if implementing the following would be a good design currently our providers and patients and healthcentres are all stored in one object and that object returns those items given differing parameters such as id or email or a search term . would it be better to have a searching object and for us to inject into that object an object that holds either providers patients or healthcentres where each of these objects have the same methods . part of the reason why i'm asking is that the searching object and the object containing the patients providers healthcentres should have an aggregation relationship but when you pass an object like def __init__ self object does this not make the relationship between these objects a composition","answers":[{"text":"hi ricky both your current approach and the suggested approach seems acceptable as i can see that they both hold their own benefits. i will not be giving a definite answer but i would like to make some suggestions 1st approach lists of providers patients and health centres in an object that allows access to the items of desired criteria - although the container object say a provides the methods for searching/querying please think about whether a really should contain the logic for searching/querying think about single responsibility principle cohesion coupling etc. - i recommend you to have a look into the data access object pattern and how it handles the case like yours. fully applying the pattern is likely to be an overkill but the motivation behind it and how it improves the design is something to take a note of. 2nd approach searching object - in this case the classes patient provider and centre should all inherit from the same parent class that abstracts over the common searching methods across the three concrete classes. and in light of ocp amp dip your searching object should only depend on such methods i.e. depend only on the higher level module . - however please note that patients providers and centres have different criteria with which they will be queried for e.g. centres by suburb providers by service type . this makes it difficult to abstract out their commonalities - in this case you should ask yourself whether this really is a flexible design i am not saying it s definitely bad just saying that you should take extra care - if this cannot be implemented easily try not to overcomplicate the code or introduce unnecessary complexity by blindly applying the design principles - sometimes simple designs are better. as for the second question passing in an object a as a parameter to the constructor of object b does not necessarily imply a composition relationship - the thing with class-to-class relationship is that it depends on the situation. a composition relationship holds whenever the lifetime of the contained object depends on the lifetime of the container object and passing in the contained object as a parameter to the constructor of the container object is just one way to allow such relationship to hold but it does not necessarily enforce it - why . cheers random babble on design please be aware that it is completely fine to use simpler design when there is no issue with the design i.e. sometimes applying the design principles too early introduces unnecessary complexity and involves you guessing the direction of change in the specs which may not be clear at the time of implementation or a change may not even occur in which case you would have had done unnecessary work - yagni . on the other hand simpler designs are often more comprehensible and can be transformed more flexibly to the changes in the requirements through refactoring. this is because the design principles are principles not laws that you must always follow. that being said some designs bring benefits immediately to the system and a simple design may be completely awful when the system itself becomes large or complex e.g. a series of if statements checking for the type of an object this suggests that you should make use polymorphism to improve the design so you must be judicious with applying this idea.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi i'm having trouble with github. i've committed my contributions and i can see them but according to my teammates my contributions are not recorded and i'm not considered a contributor. can someone help please","answers":[{"text":"i've emailed your student email in regards to this.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi is it possible to login two different types of users in one application right now our group's code is structured into patients being a composition with patientmanager and providers being a composition with providermanager etc so i made a page for logging in patients and another for logging in providers. login only works for either the patient/the provider depending on which form you have filled in first. is there a workaround to this or do i have to change how the classes are structured i.e. have patients and providers inherit from user and then define user access roles thanks. edit nevermind i changed it to inheritance and it works. however i'm still unsure on how to define user access roles properly.","answers":[{"text":"hi angela there is an example code provided for lab08 authenticationmanager.py and its usage in routes.py that handles different user permissions - please checkout it out and try to analyse how it works. please feel free to ask if you would like some help with that","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"to any who can help i'm getting an error from my redirect function call typeerror centre missing 1 required positional argument 'centre' this suggests to me that theres something wrong with what im passing into the redirect but after playing around for a while i'm still not sure what it is. the route and function are as such app.route '/centre/ lt name gt ' def centre centre name return render_template 'centre.html' result centre the html call is like this lt div gt for c in result lt a href url_for 'centre' centre c name c.name gt c lt /a gt endfor lt /div gt any advice is appreciated.","answers":[{"text":"hi joshua app.route '/centre/ lt name gt ' only parameterises the name argument since it is the only one in between the angular brackets - so in fact your centre method currently can only take in one parameter name and not centre . please have another go at fixing your issue with that in mind. hint another pair of lt gt may help please tell me if you cannot still resolve the issue.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"all i wondered is that whether it is okay for me to create a html for each provider and centre or just create one template then fill everything in","answers":[{"text":"it's fine if you want to create html for each provider. if you just use one template you will not lose mark as well.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i didn't quite get it for each provider and centre i created a html file but they are in same layout is that okay","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"it's okay. by the way if you think they are in same layout why seperate","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"with regards to getter and setter methods would it be better for the object itself to have a getter method e.g. list healthprovider.get or if we were to have a list of objects stored in a 'manager' for that manager to get the object information i.e. str healthprovider.name..","answers":[{"text":"a class that models a health-care provider e.g. class healthprovider would have getter and setter if needed methods that would return and set details about the particular provider. if you wanted to cache a list of health-care providers this would typically be stored in another class as list of providers which you would then be able to search for a particular provider by different criteria e.g. name","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"i am getting this error in my routes.py. i am unsure how to fix it werkzeug.exceptions.httpexception.wrap. lt locals gt .newcls 400 bad request keyerror 'password'","answers":[{"text":"hi aniket it is likely because you are trying to access a value of a dictionary e.g. request.form is a dictionary too with a key 'password' that does not exist this is similar to an invalid array index error for arrays. whenever you are accessing a dictionary value please make sure that the dictionary already has a corresponding key-value pair stored inside it.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"for week 9 does our uml class diagram need to include even ones that are not needed to be implemented yet i.e. rating/notes/prescriptions","answers":[{"text":"hi paulo you only need to include the ones that belong to this milestone","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"how can we implement near-match of string in python3","answers":[{"text":"hi haoran the definition of a near-match should have been provided in your acceptance criteria so it depends on how you have defined it. but in the case that you have not or if you would like hints as to implement such a functionality please have a look at the behaviour of the search engine example solution http //cgi.cse.unsw.edu.au/ cs1531/18s2/sample_project/run.cgi/. please think about what can be considered as a near match e.g. do capitalisations matter what if your search keyword is only a subset of the strings you are comparing against 'rand' in 'royal randwick' cheers","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"can we add more specific information to csv files due to the absence of name password working hour and so on","answers":[{"text":"yes you are free to modify csv files.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"do we need to have our logbook on the release branch as well","answers":[{"text":"log book does not need to be uploaded to release branch. however you log book does need a velocity chart to show user story progress.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi may i knw what does the four digit number in the second column eg.1111 in the health_centres.csv represent","answers":[{"text":"also is the fourth column phone number or","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hi yin tan we will be soon releasing an updated version of the csv files that contain the column headings","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"is it ok to ignore the class-managers when implementing them to python and just put all the methods which belong to managers under system and of course system should hold all the information it needs.","answers":[{"text":"that would still function normally yes. manager classes are mostly useful where you believe system is containing too much logic and you would like to split this logic up into cohesive classes.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"is it okay to ignore trivial methods such as getters and setters in the class diagram also should the methods in class diagram have a return type along with their parameters","answers":[{"text":"classes should have getters and setters only if needed. for example if you do not want the instance variables to be updated by clients then this class should not define setters and the instance variables are set through the constructor. hence it is important to show these methods on the class diagram. and yes methods in class diagram must define the return type along with their parameters","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"for the class diagram with a method like makebooking would you have to specify all the parameters date time etc. with the method looking like makebooking str str .. or could you have a default constructor makebooking and have setters for the other variables i.e booking.settime 15 00 and would then you need to specify all of the setter methods","answers":[{"text":"makebooking str str.. makes sense to me.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"how should methods that use property and x.setter decorators be represented in a uml diagram since the methods have the same name thank you","answers":[{"text":"great question just on the class diagram you may write get_password and set_password to indicate that your class provides a getter and a setter for the password attribute but of course you can keep the property decorators in your python code . this is acceptable since uml class diagram should be agnostic of the implementation language. also quick tip if you think you have too many getters and setters on your diagram think about whether all of them actually need to be implemented.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thank you","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi i was looking through the specs and realised there isn't a defined list of services. is that intentional","answers":[{"text":"yup your application should be able to deduce the list of all services from other csv files.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"so the program should be able to read the csv files and collect its information from there","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"yes definitely","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thank you","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"furthermore different health providers may have different workings hours and if a provider is affiliated with multiple centres then the provider will have different working hours associated with each centre how exactly does this work are the working hours the same each day or can they be different for different days of the week will the working hours with one centre be continuous or can you have something that looks like this centre 1 9am-12pm centre 2 1pm-5pm centre 1 6pm-9pm also can we add this information to the csv files as it doesn't currently seem to be specified anywhere","answers":[{"text":"for simplicity you can assume working hours are continuous and centres are open 24 hours. so you will only need to record the working hours of the health-care provider. so a provider may work 9-12 in centre 1 and 1-6 in centre 2. you can also assume that the hours don't conflict so you don't need to build in any error-handling to check if working hours across 2 centres clash","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"where do we get the working hours information from a further csv file or do we create it","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi it seems that i don't have access to commit changes to project repository under cs1531 organization. is there anyone who could help me to solve this cheers","answers":[{"text":"check that the team member who created the group project repo has given you access rights to commit.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hi we are having the same issue and everyone in our group can't push commits.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hi ellen just a quick question did you create your group on github manually and not through the github app by any chance we are trying to locate the source the error at the moment. in the meanwhile i can fix the problem for your team if you could please give me your team name and class on github thanks d","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i don't remember how we set it up it's possible. thanks it's h13a team name is csez","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"okay no worries. the access issue has been fixed for your group now by the way","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hi could you help me to solve the same issue our group name is tidehunter class is h13a. cheer","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"di is your problem fixed. are your team members able to access now","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"it works now. thank you so much.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thank you it is working d","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"a patient should be able to view their own appointments history a chronological list of their current appointments with the health providers on hams . each entry on the list should contain links to the profile pages of the corresponding health provider and the corresponding health centre. hi does this refer to two separate lists one for past appointments and one for current appointments thanks","answers":[{"text":"hi michael the appointments history just refers to the appointments you have made history here is a bit misleading i guess so actually appointments history chronological list of the patient's current appointments on hams. with regards to showing past appointments you have a freedom to either display them or not depending on what you believe is reasonable for the patients. hopefully this cleared things up but please ask if you would like further clarification.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi ae we allowed to have user stories which are not within an epic story i'm not sure whether logging in requires an entire epic story as logging in doesn't fall within our group's epic stories such as booking and searching. thanks in advance.","answers":[{"text":"hi angela it is completely fine to have a login user story under its own epic since as you said it may not fit well under other epics and it also answers the question of where you should place additional user stories if your client ever requests extra features related to login e.g. registration forgot my password to be added onto your system.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"when it says 'patient past history' in the specs as show in the picture attached does it refer to appointment history or medical history such as diabetic heart attack surgery thank you.","answers":[{"text":"hi the patient's past history refers to the chronological list of the patient's appointments with the provider with added details such as the notes taken at previous visits.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"how far beyond the specification do we need to go for the first submission in terms of things like being able to cancel a booking should we add these for later iterations","answers":[{"text":"do not implement something which is not currently required.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"can we number user stories in according to the epic stories there associated with or to show related user stories. for example have epic story 3 us3.1 3.2 3.3 etc... and even us 3.3.1/us3.3.2 to show further breaking down of the user stories or should we just keep at as 1 2 3 .....","answers":[{"text":"numbering user-stories is mainly to uniquely identify a particular user-story and use this identifier later to associate for example the set of test-cases associated with this story. your convention for numbering stories sounds quite logical and would actually help to trace a particular fine-grained user-story to the epic story it is associated with. good thinking","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"do we need to block usernames that input incorrect passwords an x amount of times within a certain time frame","answers":[{"text":"hi adam as said in the answer to the question below this is up to you and your team's discretion to implement this feature if you feel that it is reasonable. however i personally feel that it is less important than other features that you have been asked to implement in the specification and i would recommend considering it as an optional/extension task after you have delivered higher priority user stories. nevertheless it would be great if you do have this additional feature included in the final product","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"is there a limit on how far in advance a user can book an appointment and therefore how far in advance the doctors availability must be given for","answers":[{"text":"as this is a granular detail that has not been covered by the specification of the assignment your team should discuss together to come up with a reasonable assumption regarding this matter - any decision is acceptable as long as it is well supported by reasons and value to the customer is well considered in the decision making. also please make sure to include your final decision in the assumptions list as requested in the assignment specs.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"does a user need to be able to log out in iteration 1","answers":[{"text":"once you have implemented a login feature for the system logout should be very easy to implement. also logging-in and logging-out seem like features that are much better implemented together for easier testing and usability reasons so i would highly recommend doing so for the iteration 1.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"about viewing appointment's history does the user only see their current appointments or also all previous/past appointments as well","answers":[{"text":"our model solution offered a way for a user to see their current appointments. once the doctor had been seen this appointment would be removed from their current appointment dashboard. a user however was able to see their past history with the doctor e.g notes taken by the doctor medication prescribed by clicking on the history tab. you can implement this functionality in different ways however the key point is a user needs to be able view their current appointments and also have the capability to view the doctor's notes in their previous appointments","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"what is the give command for the assignment our group has finished the tasks required for us to complete for this week. we've uploaded everything to github but what is the give command","answers":[{"text":"the give submission has not been setup. it will be done shortly.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thanks. do we all need to give the assignment or just one of us","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"just one member from the team.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi for the user stories do we have to submit them with some kind of template i remember something about this briefly mentioned in the lectures but i'm not too sure. thanks","answers":[{"text":"a template has been uploaded to the assignment folder under the group project iteration 1","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"for the car search i am unable to get the make and model. if i try and create a post method the page sends a 405 error saying i can't use that. but if i implement it without the post method it sends a 400 bad request error. i don't know how i'm supposed to run the search.","answers":[{"text":"hi dante there are two ways you could go about solving your issue 1. using post method the 405 error means that your flask app server is not supporting the post method for that route and this is so for your case because routes in flask only support the get method by default. you can fix this simply by specifying which methods should be supported as a parameter to the route decorator e.g. app.route '/login' methods 'get' 'post' - now this will allow both get and post methods to be used. 2. using get method not recommended for security reasons you may also choose to send form inputs via get method in which case the input values can be retrieved by doing something like make request.args.get 'make' . not recommended cheers","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"currently having this error. i already checked localhost 5000 and it gives me not found except this error keeps showing up.","answers":[{"text":"hi jack try changing your port number to something like 5001 or 5002 i.e. to a port number that may not be already in use .","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"whenever i run pytest on my test_make_booking file it raises an import error a module named src.authenicationmanager does not exist .also i copied all of this code from sample test image provided under week9 labs. i can't figure out why it is raising such an error and how to tackle this error","answers":[{"text":"hi satvik here is a quick checklist you may want to follow - please delete your __pycache__ and .pytest_cache files as they may be from a different machine e.g. mine - please check that your authenticationmanager.py is located under the folder 'src' - please make sure to use pytest instead of unittest for this lab also you should import dummyauthenticationmanager instead of authenticationmanager for testing try using authenticationmanager instead to see what happens if you are still having issues please let me know","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"didn't do any good. i went through your checklist made sure that authenticationmanger exists under src folder and also imported dummyauthenticationmanager and pytest but i still got this error. is py.test test_make_booking.py command correct","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"as you have mentioned this issue might be due to pytest not recognising the root directory of your program correctly. please try python3 -m pytest test_make_booking.py. also please make sure that you are running the commands from the root directory . by the way py.test test_make_booking.py is a valid command too except it may not work in cases like yours.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"cheers su it's finally working. as you said my pytest command was incorrect. i used python3 -m pytest test_make_booking.py and it worked.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"for lab08 i just downloaded all the given code and installed requirements.txt but it says theres a syntax error on line 36 in car.py i don't know whats wrong with it though return f'car lt self.name self.model gt ' syntaxerror invalid syntax","answers":[{"text":"hi andrew please check whether you have the correct version of python 3.6 installed on your machine and that you are running the correct version of python also python3 run.py . also please check whether you have edited any code above the line 36 and revert the changes to avoid the syntax error.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"for lab 9 task 1 part b we are meant to define exception handling for when the user doesn't insert a date for the booking in make_booking and check_fee . however if the user doesn't input a start/end date the program crashes before it reaches those functions. it crashes in an inbuilt function of datetime strptime . since it crashes inside a function we cant access how are we meant to do this section of the task","answers":[{"text":"hi anthony and andrew one option is let those functions make_booking and check_fee take in the dates as strings i.e. directly take in the form inputs so that the functions may be fully responsible for the input validation. if you are not satisfied with the design you may choose to abstract out the whole form validation logic and delegate such to another function/class. also you should not need to change the way the date is read in from the form.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"this is something that i have been struggling with as well. the error seems to be in the 'check' section. do we have to change the way the date is read in from the form","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"i'm trying to run the starter code i've made minimal changes on my own machine but i keep getting the error no module named flask_login . i've set up a virtual environment and installed flask so i don't know why it can't find the module","answers":[{"text":"what changes did you make anything to imports also did you make sure to set the virtual environment to python3.6 . please also check pip3 freeze for flask-login installation.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"didn't change anything to imports. my virtual environment is set to python3.7 and running pip3 freeze shows flask-login 0.4.1 no idea what this means","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"try python version - m pip install flask i had a similar issue","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"in the method add_booking in car.py def add_booking self booking self.bookings.append booking should it be self. _booking .append booking instead","answers":[{"text":"yes it should be.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi i'm confused about car make. it seems like in car class we only know the name model and rego. and the function car_search take the argument name and model. so i'm confused about how to search by make","answers":[{"text":"sorry i believe that name is actually equivalent to the make.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"commits in last 48 hours will lose marks - gt does that mean we will lose marks if most of the commits are in the last 48 hours or does it mean that any commits within that time period will lose us marks","answers":[{"text":"hi it means that deductions will apply if most of the commits are made in the last 48 hours as consistent work and dev-ethics is one focus of this group project .","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"error 404 not found i did run using python3 run.py but i got this error instead the requested url was not found on the server. if you entered the url manually please check your spelling and try again. anyone can help me with this problem thanks","answers":[{"text":"hi mikamocha have you set up the route for an empty url by any chance please check if you have something like this app.route '/' def index pass the app.route '/' above a function any name is good is what you need to actually make the url http //127.0.0.1 5000/ valid.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i am getting the same problem sometimes idk why can somebody help","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hey dhruv to help with this issue could you describe how you are set up using vlab ssh or running locally . also ensure that it is indeed not working for a simple example like ian's above one otherwise it would have to do with how you wrote it rather than your set up. lastly attempt to add or remove the slash at the end of your url on the browser and checking if that may fix it","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"nope i fixed my app.route when i ran it on my terminal.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"adding collaborator i want to add my partner as a collaborator to the repo so we can work on the code together but i cannot since i do not own the repo. is there a way around this","answers":[{"text":"hi arthur if you are asking about the week 6/7 lab the lab must be done individually - so no collaborators","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"how do add in a check for if time is valid or not in lab06-07","answers":[{"text":"invlaid time is anything that is not a non negative number. you can check for this in routes after retrieving from request.form","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"it worked fine in cse lab but when i got home. it gave me this error have no idea how to fix it. please have a look ty","answers":[{"text":"hi jiahao the error message says address already in use - this usually happens when you already have another process running on your machine that is using the same port number as the one your python program is trying to use. so a quick solution to this is to simply change the port number for your program. try app.run port 8181 debug true . cheers","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hi i inserted the line app.run port 8181 debug true in routes.py beneath from app import app but i still keep encountering the 'address is already in use' error are there any ways i can fix this thanks","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"please try to avoid doing app.run ... in the routes.py because we have separated the starting code into three different files routes run server so that each of them can serve a distinct purpose. so instead app.run should be located in run.py and in fact there should already be one in that file so you only need to modify it a bit to resolve your issue. please tell me if this would still not solve your issue.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"ah right yep that makes sense. thanks it's working now","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hi i inserted the app.run ... into run.py and i'm still getting the same error. how can i fix this thanks.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"one thing you could try first is to using different port numbers 8080 8081 8082 ... or even restarting your machine or killing the python processes running in the background but if none of those work the easiest way for me to figure out the problem would be to check your code on github if you could put it up on there.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i have tried different port numbers and i'm not permitted to kill the python processes. i'm worried this same issue will happen for my group project. edit after i restart my computer i can run flask 2 times before the same error occurs. also when i go to localhost 5000 someone else's interest calculator is there instead","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hi it took me a while to experiment with things. i realised that it is very easy to encounter such issues when you are running your flask app on the cse machines or via vlab because the ports are being shared across multiple users as far as i can see it may be false or are not being recycled properly. so i would recommend you to run your flask programs on your own device to avoid such issues.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"can someone helps me figure out why this happens and how to fix this. thank u. gt","answers":[{"text":"yup please read the previous post or quick fix do app.run port 5001 debug true in run.py .","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"ty gt","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"unable to git clone the repo. not sure what i'm doing wrong here","answers":[{"text":"hmm the repo does indeed exist you are a collaborator and i am able to clone it myself. you are using the https link however you are getting an error before you can even authenticate. my guess is you have set it up to automatically sign in but with a different github account than the collaborator with a quick search you may be using osxkeychain to do that if that rings a bell you might to disable/change that","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thanks i used the ssh key instead and it seemed to work.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi. i'm trying to use html and flask at home. but when i open html at chrome some parts of it don't work. even when i use the example given in the lecture it can not work properly as in the lecture. v-lab doesn't work also. is there something wrong or i should download something","answers":[{"text":"opening html as google chrome is not the same as running a web application. you are essentially viewing a template of your web app without any real functionality. you will need to use python3 run.py to start your server which will then provide you a link to the web-app. i would suggest having a look at how run.py is implemented.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"by the way i got this error. do i need to solve this environment production warning do not use the development server in a production environment. use a production wsgi server instead.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"it is fine.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"okay i will try thank you","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi i got this notice on my github. should i reapply but i forgot what to say on how you plan to use github","answers":[{"text":"github education account expires because they think you are no longer offically enrolled in unsw. for the purposes of our couse you do not need an education account. however if you wish to have an education account for your own personal use then reapply but you will need to send it official course enrolment proof in addition to supplying an email address with a unsw domain.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"okay thank you","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"you do not need an education account anymore to complete labs. personally mine has also expired...","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"haha. thank you","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"i'm having problems pushing my files into git. i don't have the education pack yet so i've made my own public repo on git followed the instructions on there and on the git faq but im getting this error. after trying that command and failing stack overflow told me to git push -u origin master but that gave me this error the same error as git push --set-upstream origin master","answers":[{"text":"you no longer need the education pack to import the labs. instead of using your account import will now import to the organisation repository. i also suspect that you got that error as you probably did not specify origin or do git init before attempting to gt git push -u origin master","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i followed those instructions prior to those screenshots. either way i tried to import the labs again after renaming my previous lab files and it wont let me clone the ssh.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"did you set up your ssh key at home","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i did the week1 lab in my week2 lab on my personal computer so everything should be set up correctly","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"if you have set up your ssh key on your machine then then make sure you do exactly the following go to https //cgi.cse.unsw.edu.au/ cs1531/github/run.cgi/labs select lab02 click import or replace . follow the link that will be shown soon after. it should direct you to github. the exact repository should be named cs1531-lab02. import with ssh. if you still have issues navigate to your github settings and ssh keys delete your current one and setup again following lab01 instructions.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"it wont let me. it tells me i need to have at least an education account edit i used the link on the side to access the labs on github but still wont let me clone it. i'll try to re-setup now.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"trinh we did do a github infrastructure change on monday night. previously when you did an import the repo would have been created under your github account which would have needed an education account to be able to do so but under the current setup if you do an import the repo is created under the organisation. if you have not done the import after monday night i suggest you do an import again.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"could you send a screenshot of this it shouldn't require one anymore...","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i can access it on the link on the webcms page but the link you gave me didnt work. but i ended up deleting the ssh keys and doing the setup again and it works properly now. thank you for your help","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"that's weird however that is good to hear","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"i can't push files to my github account. how should i connect this to github","answers":[{"text":"it would have been better that you imported the lab from https //cgi.cse.unsw.edu.au/ cs1531/github/run.cgi/labs then imported to github and cloned it into your machine. otherwise you would need to follow these instructions https //help.github.com/articles/adding-an-existing-project-to-github-using-the-command-line/","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi i keep getting this error when i'm trying to import abstract classes","answers":[{"text":"richard is correct. for context python calls python 2 which does not have abc but instead has something called abcmeta . stick with python3 and you'll be good","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"oh ok thanks","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"use python3 filename so python3 classes.py","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi is logging in a use case that should be included with most other use cases it seems a bit messy but at the same time it makes sense to do so so i'm not sure. thanks","answers":[{"text":"yup login is definitely a use-case that must be included in all primary use-cases since every user must login in order to perform the actions they want . you can always tidy up the lines by letting them share the same backbone like so","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"but how can we distinguish use cases that are specific to librarians not other users","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"if you are saying that doing the above wouldnt differentiate librarians from other users my answer is that it doesnt stop you from doing so. if you meant it in general the answer to this question is in the lecture notes and it may be a good idea to look up similar examples online but just to give a few hints please think about how you can represent a general user as well as a librarian who can interact with extra use cases on top of the general use cases.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thanks for your reply. also if the user only initiates 'login' which is included by all other use cases would 'login' become the user's goal/primary use case","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"in general you have an option to have the 'login' use-case as either primary initiated directly or not. and this is the case for this assignment as well - since 'login' by itself does not deliver the core values of the system to the user at least in my opinion yet it is an integral part of the system at the same time plus as you said the user can just login and do nothing too. so please feel free to do it either way although you might want to be consistent with the lecture notes which has the 'login' use-case as not-primary. d","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thanks","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"how do we upload the diagram in draw.io to github i tried to save it onto the local machine first but the file appeared as a bunch of text/code and when i tried to do export as pdf to my local machine it couldn't open the file afterwards. also when i tried to export it directly to github it needed some kind of autherisation which got me failing to export it.","answers":[{"text":"you can submit via give either on webcms3 or using ssh to get the lab machine terminal. to submit on webcms3 you go to assignments then click make submission. follow instructions and you should be ok. if you can't open the pdf you may not have a pdf reader like adobe installed.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"you need to click file gt export gt pdf. also this isn't being uploaded to github is it just to give","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"in the use case diagram are we allowed use actor generalisation to make things cleaner","answers":[{"text":"yes absolutely yes","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"for the use case diagram the part about returning a copy it says when a copy of an item is returned the copy will be automatically loaned to the user at the front of the waiting list and they will receive a notification... which i thought it means as soon as the copy is returned it will appear as burrowed by another person on the waiting list so its status is still on loan . but then it also says the notified user follows the same steps to loan the item . which got me wonder what if the notified user say he no longer wanted to burrow that copy doesn't follow the steps to loan the book after receiving the email in that case is the copy still loaned to him automatically i'm mainly confused about the copy will be automatically loaned to the user bit since if it's already automatically loaned to another user the loaning process should be already done in the system internally then why does the user still need to follow the steps to loan the copy also do we consider the notified user as an external participant with a participate line drawn between send email and the first user on the waiting list or since the notified user will then login to the system and follow the whole burrowing process again in order to loan the copy he is simply a regular initiating actor user which will just go back to the start of the diagram so we don't have to include more stuff after the send email use case thanks","answers":[{"text":"hi shangjie as for the first question you may assume either way - as long as you write down your assumptions next to your diagrams. whether or not you assume that the copy will be automatically loaned the use-case for sending an email does not require the first user on the waiting list to contribute in the process of emailing and even if they are indirectly involved with the process since they will be receiving the email this is external to the system hence they do not need to be lt lt participating gt gt with the use-case. hopefully this cleared things up for you d","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"ok that makes sense thanks ian","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"is multi - inheritance allowed for example if we had a book copy object could this object inherent properties from both 'book' and 'item copy' or should this be avoided","answers":[{"text":"although multi-inheritance is possible in some programming languages the design itself is strongly discouraged. please consider whether a multi-inheritance is really necessary and whether other types of relationships association aggregation composition may be used instead to solve your problem. also you could also consider whether such a class is necessary in the first place.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi just for clarification does for use-case diagrams only lines associated with lt lt include gt gt and lt lt extend gt gt stereo types must have arrow-heads all the other are solid lines with no arrow-heads. mean that all lines in our diagrams are to be solid i think in the examples shown in the lectures lt lt include gt gt and lt lt extends gt gt were dotted lines with arrow-heads. thank you. d","answers":[{"text":"hi it's - for lt lt include gt gt and lt lt extend gt gt dotted lines with arrow-heads - for lt lt initiate gt gt and lt lt participate gt gt solid lines with no arrow-heads also quick tip about the direction of arrowheads for you and other students who may read this post - lt lt include gt gt goes from the primary to the secondary use-case a --include-- gt b means b is always performed as a part of a - lt lt extend gt gt goes from the secondary to the primary use-case a lt --extend-- b means b is optionally performed as a part of a here by primary and secondary i am simply referring to which use-case is 'more important' in general.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thank you so much also just wondering when you said please make sure to state your assumptions somewhere on your artefacts somewhere clearly visible do you mean we can write out our assumptions in our appendix sorry for the questions just want to make sure","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"since you are only allowed to submit the diagrams in .pdf format you may write your assumptions somewhere next to your diagrams or on the next page which you may call 'appendix' .","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"can a certain 'book' for example harry potter have both a physical copy item copy and a digital copy e-copy thanks","answers":[{"text":"yes an item may have both a physical copy and a digital copy available and they would be under the same name.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"ok thanks","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"for the class diagram is it allowed to have a such diagram a class has both inheritance and composition","answers":[{"text":"yes definitely you can first think of it without the inheritance and then with the inheritance it just means that the subclasses of the composing class also inherit such relationship as well.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"ok thank you","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"can we cherry pick what attributes we want stored in another related class - e.g. some attributes in the class 'item' include lt title publisher availablecopies... gt but i only want the attribute of lt title gt to be stored in the class 'loaneditemcopies'.","answers":[{"text":"you will find out there are many ways to implement a class to meet specifications but the hard part is figuring out what is the best for your situation. for example by storing only the title this means there would need to be some function a method to search for the original item via name string if you are implementing via code. you may choose at your discretion what attributes should be held by associated classes as long as it meets requirements but think about the implications of doing so.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"for the inheritance relationship do we need to specify the cardinality in the class diagram","answers":[{"text":"no there should be cardinality on associations which include aggregation and composition . there is no instantiation of abstract classes thus cardinality is pointless for inheritance.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thanks just one more question. if i define item as a class then it has two sub-class e-copy and physical item copy . so the relationship between them will be inheritance right but as shown in the assi-specification it says an item may have 0 or more physical copy. does this mean the relationship between them is a kind of association","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i would think carefully about the relationship between an item and its copy and e-copy. in your spec it states items can be journals ect... these are types of items. would a copy or e-copy be a type-of item in the same idea a journal is a type of item.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"cardinality is not specified for inheritance relationships as inheritance shows if an instance of a sub-class can also be treated as a type of an instance of the parent class. cardinality is only required for associations which could also be aggregation or composition","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thank you","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"will we be allowed to use enumeration in our class diagrams e.g. for storing genre names thanks","answers":[{"text":"yes you can defintely use enumeration types in your class diagram for genre names. good thinking","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"i have a question about the wording of this assignment. from the specification return an item copy - a borrower may return the borrowed item copy. when a copy of an item is returned the copy will be automatically loaned to the user at the front of the waiting list and they will receive a notification of the new loan of the item copy via email. the notified user follows the same steps to loan the item. should this instead be the copy will be automatically reserved for the user at the front of the waiting list as it currently reads a loan is to be created for the user who then must initiate a loan via the usual steps after being notified but initiating the steps for a loan would be redundant if the loan already automatically exists if the user is at the top of the waiting list after the item copy is returned please clarify if i'm reading this incorrectly thank you","answers":[{"text":"hi sophie sorry for not being too clear in the specification. i originally meant that the loan is immediately transferred to the person at the front of the waiting list so counting the days for the new loan would start from the moment the previous holder returns it - more specifically from the moment the librarian clicks the 'return' button for the copy . however you may choose to design the system for the other case where the user would first be notified of the copy's availability whence then the user would be required to follow the steps to loan the item. however this poses a slight issue because the user may take arbitrarily long time to initiate the loan and it would adversely affect the rest of the people in the waiting list - so you may need a measure for such issues if you assume the second case. either way please make sure to state your assumptions somewhere on your artefacts somewhere clearly visible . if you still have any confusions regarding this please let me know. d","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thanks for clearing it up. can we model the transfer of the loan as an include from the say inform waiting list use case to the loan an itemcopy use case thanks","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"it may seem reasonable but not quite. the loan an itemcopy use-case is supposed to be a use-case initiated by an actor who is borrowing the copy so there is a risk of confusion if you have an lt lt include gt gt from inform waiting list to loan an itemcopy because then it may not be clear whether the libriarian who has initiated the chain/set of use-cases is borrowing the copy or if the ownership of the copy is being transferred to the person in the waiting list. also if you are assuming the first case the procedure for loaning the copy may differ from simply transferring the loan. if you are assuming the second case the informing is caused by the librarian whereas the borrowing is initiated by the customer so they are considered to be separate use-case scenarios. basically please try another way to represent the scenario so that it may be clearer to other people who may view your artefacts. cheers","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"is visibility required for the class diagram for this assignment because in the sample class diagram from the lecture they were all '-'. thanks in advance.","answers":[{"text":"yes modelling the right access modifier is essential in the class diagram and this assignment as well","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thanks for your reply. i'm uncertain about what exactly gets counted as visible or not considering that there are some actors that can access the information and some cannot. also i'm not too sure why all the access modifiers in the sample diagram are on private in that case.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hi winston i believe you are currently confused with the concept of encapsulation and how this is applied to the classes. we often encapsulate an object's state data by declaring them as private '-' and thereby preventing other classes from directly accessing to the object's attributes. however this does not mean that we are completely restricting the access to such attributes but we are actually providing indirect access to them through the object's methods which are declared public. this way any access to the object's internal state from outside is controlled e.g. the banking system example . so relating back to your question even though the attributes may be declare private in the class diagram any relevant data about objects in your system should still be accessible in some ways through public interfaces methods of the objects. if you are still having troubles understanding the concept i recommend asking for further clarifications at consultations it really helps d","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"does that mean we should make all attributes private '-' in our class diagram knowing that it is better form for other classes to interact with them through method calls","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"yup that's right","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi can you provide more detail on the process of 'renewal' the specification only says if there are no other users who have reserved the item then the borrower can renew the loan i.e. extend the due date at most once for an additional period of 7 days. and says nothing about how e.g. clicking button speaking to librarian etc.","answers":[{"text":"as the borrower is already in possession of the book you may assume that the borrower can do an online renewal e.g. clicking a button provided there are no other users who have reserved the item","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"cool thanks.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"in the new notice there were some clarifications for assignment 1. on the notice it said for use-case diagrams only lines associated with lt lt initiate gt gt and lt lt extend gt gt stereo types must have arrow-heads all the other are solid lines with no arrow-heads. what about lt lt include gt gt doesn't lt lt include gt use arrow-heads the only difference being that instead of solid lines it uses a dotted line","answers":[{"text":"sorry minha that was my typo error. it should say lt lt include gt gt and lt lt extend gt gt . i have modified the notice. thanks for bringing it to my attention","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"initiates/participates between actors say i have a database of waiting lists for each book and an email system both of which are external secondary actors. the specs require an email to be sent to the first person in the waiting list when a book becomes available. since this process is automated internally there shouldn't be a secondary use case specifying to remove the user from the waiting list. so is it ok to draw an lt lt initiate gt gt between the waiting list and email actor or will i need to link the external actors to a use case","answers":[{"text":"hi arthur you just said the answer before the question the process of emailing the next person in the waiting is handled internally which means it should lie within the system boundary. so in fact you would need the actors to participate in the use cases for processing the reservations and sending emails please note that you are depicting the interactions between the system and its actors and not the interaction between the actors outside the system .","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"for the class diagram is the 'copy' mentioned in the librarian function the same as 'item copy' borrowed by a user","answers":[{"text":"yes.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thanks","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"i get this error session 18s2 classrun directory /import/kamen/3/cs1531/18s2.work/assignment01/wed18-bongo/ does not exist login z5205847 stuid 5205847 class cs1531 last system error no such file or directory no submission made.","answers":[{"text":"hi the submissions should be working now could you all please try again please let me know if it still doesn't seem to work .","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i got the same.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"oop sorry about that. i will work on fixing that right now i'll notify you again when it's fixed . thanks","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"mine has worked now i actually had named the files incorrectly earlier so not sure if that was the issue.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"could you please clarify that the funtionality of search catalogue is public to anyone or only available after logged in","answers":[{"text":"you may assume that the search catalogue functionality is only accessible when logged in for simplicity. but if you would like the other way i.e. public to anyone then please make a note of this assumption somewhere clearly visible in your artefacts.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thank you","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"am i right in saying that the student/staff plays no part in returning an item copy in the library system and that only the librarian has access to do that because when i return a book to the library i don't ever access the library system to tell it i've returned the book. i'm just a bit confused since the return an item copy functional requirement is not listed exclusively under the librarian functions in the assignment spec. if that is so do i have to state the assumption that the user doesn't touch the library system to return an item copy","answers":[{"text":"you make a very valid point here anthony. it is the account or actor which does it that matters. for example in a restaurant when you place an order for food the waiter is the one interacting with the system. the specs state the librarian and click return to indicate the borrower has returned the book.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"for the use case diagram are use cases that could be related to borrowing e.g. renewing a physical copy or paying overdue fees an extension of borrowing or an initiation from the user thanks","answers":[{"text":"renewing a book or payment of over-due fees are use-cases distinct to the use-case of borrowing a book. hence they would be treated as distinct use-cases initiated by the actor","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"do we treat the database of items users etc. as an actor or assume that it can be accessed from any use case in the system diagram","answers":[{"text":"hi michael you may choose either way either to show it as an actor or assume that it is an implicit implementation detail. representing a database as an actor indicates that it lies outside of the system which provides an additional detail regarding the system's layout or on the other side it may be an unnecessary restriction to the implementation . however when there are too many use-cases that involve database access associations with a database actor could clutter up the diagram. in such a case i advise not including a db in the diagram because it makes the diagram less cluttered and helps bring more focus to more important parts of the diagram. plus interaction of a use-case with the database can often be deduced easily from its description/name.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i used an actor called library database but it just participates in everything and makes my whole diagram complicated. do we have to include it","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"as i suggested above the benefit of including a database actor note database cannot be a use-case so can only be an actor is usually minimal. it is not a requirement for you to include databases in your use-case diagrams.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"are people who have borrowed books or have overdue books able to borrow/reserve other books","answers":[{"text":"hi ricky for any granular details regarding the requirements missing in the specs as in your case you may fill it in with your own assumptions/interpretations as long as they are sensible and are written down somewhere on your artefacts for the tutors when marking . although it is a good idea to think thoroughly about the requirements for the purposes of drawing the diagrams please first ask yourself about the question you made is it something that needs to be modelled in a use-case/class diagram or is it something that you would consider during implementation","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thank you for the reply. i was mainly asking because it seemed like for some of the use cases the actors would have to be specifically borrowers or people who have reserved books. is this the case or am i overcomplicating the diagram.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"in our case you do not need to distinguish the 'borrowers' and 'people on waiting lists' from the regular customers it is because these things are better represented as different 'states' of the customers rather than as different 'types' of customers. hence these aspects of the system would be lying closer to the implementation details and further from a high level overview of the system's use-cases which implies that trying to portray these on the use-case diagram would unnecessarily overcomplicate the diagram . please let me know if you would like further clarifications d","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"is sending emails an internal action of our system or it involves a third party thank in advance","answers":[{"text":"hi yeeru that is actually a very good question to ask. you may assume that the process of sending an email is handled by an external system i.e. a third party like gmail . however even in such a case the system would still require a module to interact with the emailing system.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"sorry i didn't quite get the last bit about the module to interact with the emailing system.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"sorry about the lack of clarity i just meant that in reality you would still need to write some code to communicate with and make use of the external emailing system since there is no other way to 'send' an email without implementing anything related to it . also a 'module' simply refers to a piece of code that provides a particular functionality e.g. sending an email via an external system . please let me know if you would like further explanation.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thanks for your explanation i get it now. in this assignment we don't need to show details about interaction between our system and the external system right","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hm... i wonder... it may be a good idea to revise on the lecture notes.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thanks","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"under user only staff members and students of unsw are able to use the library and log in. are librarians staff members or their own entities thank you","answers":[{"text":"a librarian is a unsw staff member authorized to carry out administrative functions on the library system. so yes they are staff members . however the real difficulty with this idea arises in code implementation how do we distinguish library staff from teaching staff for this diagram think about if it makes sense to distinguish different staff or not. side note this assignment does not lead on to the group assignment don't stress too much","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"ok so that imply that librarians can also use the library facilities. right","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"note that in the specs staff members and students both come under the heading user . whatever functionality users have both staff and students have. hopefully that can answer your question. i'm not giving exact answers as i want people to derive it themselves.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"great thanks","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"is there a 4pm consultation today","answers":[{"text":"yeah i remember that the lecturer said there would be some at 4 but it doesn't seem to have been announced yet..","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"the consultation is 1-2pm on fridays. there will be an extra one at 4pm today.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"i went to the consultation room today but no-one was there. are consultations not running this friday thanks","answers":[{"text":"it wasnt on today sorry for the confusion. i will be doing a consult now 2pm in 403 if it is needed. in future weeks it will be 1pm","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"if i come right now will you still be here thanks","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"yes come now","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"are there any more consultation times i find both clashing with my timetable.","answers":[{"text":"consultation time on friday is now 1-2.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"will there be consultations today at 2pm in the 403 room","answers":[{"text":"yes consultations are on today at 2 00 in 403.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"is the consultation at 2pm available today i'm inside room 405 atm not sure if the consultation is open.","answers":[{"text":"consultation now at 2.30 room 203 level 2 k1","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"so consultations are weekly 2.30 room 203 level 2 k17 every thursday.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi are quizzes one attempt only i assumed quizzes would be like 1521 where you can change your responses after so i submitted even though i was unsure on some questions but then immediately got my marks back. thanks","answers":[{"text":"hi please forget what i said before. luckily only for this week's quiz you are allowed to resubmit multiple times","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hi angela unfortunately the quizzes are one attempt only.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"are there any help sessions","answers":[{"text":"hi joshua you can attend consultations for help or to ask questions.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"is the final exam completely on paper the course outline states programming exercises will be included but students from previous semester stated that the final exam was conducted completely on paper.","answers":[{"text":"hi victoria the final exam is most likely to be conducted primarily on computers on paper for drawing diagrams this semester. indeed in 17s2 the exam was completely on paper but we have moved to using computers since 18s1. more details on the final exam will be provided later throughout the course. cheers ian","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"this is good to hear","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i think the final exam is on paper yes. similar to past comp courses that i have done. but i think there will be an assignment part where you create a web app using python and flask. so i guess that could fall under programming exercises or perhaps that is the weekly programming labs like on leetcode","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hey my friday tute will clash with the lecture if it goes longer than 3 hours but i would still want to attend the 4th hour. is it okay to change to another tute/lab session instead","answers":[{"text":"yo each lecture will go on for only 2 hours. what aarthi meant by the 4th hour is the 2nd hour of the friday lecture - so you should not worry about it clashing with your tutorial. sorry about the confusion d","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"when will quizzes be released will it be weekly","answers":[{"text":"first quiz will be released in week 4. there are 3 quizzes in all for this semester weeks 4 8 12.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"i'm having trouble understanding these two errors","answers":[{"text":"for handle_guess it should check 1. it is on the list 2. then remove it if it is you can't list.remove a where a doesn't exist in the first place within the list. for the other one i believe your find_closest function is returning none instead of 1 for that specific test case.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thank you","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"what is test_cheater doing","answers":[{"text":"hey alex it simply knows all the answers already and just guesses the correct ones in order and hence beats the game in the least number of guesses possible.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hmm then i don't know why i keep failing the test i can print the values and run through the program in 3 inputs and it works just fine. i think test_cheater is trying to cheat my program assertion error i guessed 1 but is was not in 1 7 10","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hi alex that error is generated if your code printed something like 'the closest number to your guess is lower/higher ' - which implies that your code did not behave correctly because the cheater always makes correct guesses yet somehow you are printing the message that is for when the user has guessed a wrong value. hopefully this will help you solve the issue d","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"just a curious question i remembered week 2's lab exercise uses this command pytest to check whether our program is correct or not. why is this week different what's the purpose of using the python3 in front and the flag -m python3 -m pytest","answers":[{"text":"hi muhammad there were a few reasons why 1. sometimes 'pytest' would run in an incorrect python version causing issues python3 -m pytest always uses python version 3 2. sometimes 'pytest' would not be able to find the files to test e.g. import error could not find the module... due to the test path not being configured correctly - whereas the -m ensures that the test runs on the current directory 3. it just worked without causing issues more often than just using 'pytest' i hope it helped d","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"for previous weeks when i import a lab via the link given it created a repository labelled my_username/cs1531-lab.... for this week's however it creates a repository labelled cs1531/lab03-starter_my_username is this supposed to happen","answers":[{"text":"yes imports will now be done under the organisation repository so students no longer require an education account.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"ok thank you there's no need to move the previous week's labs into new repositories as well right","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"no it should be fine.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"everytime i run pytest now nothing happens what should i do","answers":[{"text":"hi joshua could you please try testing individual files by 'python3 -m pytest lt test file name gt ' and tell me what happens afterwards","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"when i try python3 -m pytest test_count.py or python3 -m pytest count.py it looks like the image above","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hi mr park pytest appears to be working on number_list and fib but not for count.py when using pytest for count.py it says collecting 0 items and just waits","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hi the error seems most likely to be with pytest and pytest-mock being outdated although there could be many other possible reasons . could you please re-installing pytest and pytest-mock to the latest version for python3.6 by doing 'pip3 install pytest' and 'pip3 install pytest-mock' just for a double check the versions i currently have are pytest-3.6.0 and mock-1.10.0. please let me know if this doesn't solve the issue in which case i might have to inspect your source code .","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hi i did the pip3 installs and after have versions pytest-3.4.2 and mock-1.7.1 still the same issue","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"okay then could you please push your current work to github so that i may inspect it and see what is going on and please tell me your github username so that i could locate it asap.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"my github username is yveljj","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hi joshua after inspecting your code it seems like you have an 'infinite loop' inside your code. please try to rectify this issue by being careful of where you are incrementing your counter 'j'.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"ok thanks","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"when i run pytest it stays like this and doesn't show any result i 've put the if __name__ '__main__' statement to prevent breaking and does the 25 mean i get 25 for this task or it has done 25 testing","answers":[{"text":"your solution to fibonacci is very inefficient which is why the tests are hanging. note that python has implemented at 1000 default limit on recursion depth. your solution is incapable of calculating very large kth fibonacci terms. try utilise the dictionary to reuse already calculated terms in your solution. percentage should reflect total tests which have been completed not marks.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"regarding the percentage does that mean that when running pytest it should say 100 if no errors came up thanks","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"when a test fails it will pop out in output in red text. if not you passed them all don't focus on the percentages.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"ok get it. thanks","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"does pytest test our program to see if we programmed correctly i ask because i run pytest and it says '12 passed' but when i look at the percentages next to each test file some its 25 33 and 100 for count.py fib.py test_number_list respecively. wondering if that's how it is meant to be or my program is still wrong thank you","answers":[{"text":"hi aran the 's are like a progress bar indicating how many of the test cases you have passed so far - so intermediary numbers do not matter as long as you acquired 100 in the end. and if it says you have passed all the test cases without any errors then you have congrats d","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"sweet thanks","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"i was stuck here . and wondering what to do with it.","answers":[{"text":"hi yuqin the lab starter code for lab02 is also available for direct download from the 'labs' page. since you may be in a hurry only an hour to go until it's due please download from there as an emergency measure but also please make sure to create your own git repo on github and push your work to there by 11.59pm.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi are we allowed to use list function like list.reverse ... for number_list task","answers":[{"text":"list.reverse reverses in place and returns nothing. for a one line solution it is tough. try the inbuilt reversed function which you can combine with list inbuilt function. alternatively use slicing.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"the more robust test causes all three types of the count tests to fail but passes all tests on the old count_test script. in the new test script the characters were added onto the third string. from the error messages it seems my program interprets these 3 chars as one char hence the length of the dictionary i used was 2 less. currently my code checks if the char is in the dictionary if not it appends to the dictionary. then the key's value is incremented by 1. i am wondering if this was intentionally done if so some guidance into solving this issue is much appreciated.","answers":[{"text":"hi arthur i am really sorry about the confusion - i really shouldn't have included the apostrophe in the test script because it is being interpreted differently on different editors amp text displays. could you please try clicking 'download' directly from the labs page instead of opening it up on webcms and copy-pasting if it does not solve the problem please let me know i will make a fix to the test script.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i have tested your solution the chars now show up as a regular apostrophe and is able to pass the tests thank you.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"ah also it is okay if your code has passed the old test_count script you do not need to test it on the newer one. the more 'robust' test script doesn't refer to how thorough the testing is but actually to the fact that it allows for different ordering among the characters that have the same count - so in fact it's a more generous version of the old test.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"what does it mean by write code to accept user input do i not use input","answers":[{"text":"try using if __name__ '__main__' and place your input and print statements below. make sure this is define outside the fib_sequence function.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"i have set the python3 as python3.6 but how could i install the pytest i have tried 'pip3 install pytest'","answers":[{"text":"what happens when you try pip3 install pytest","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"it says 'successfully installed atomicwrites-1.1.5 attrs-18.1.0 more-itertools-4.2.0 pathlib2-2.3.2 pluggy-0.7.1 py-1.5.4 pytest-3.7.1 setuptools-40.0.0 six-1.11.0' in the end when i use 'python3 -m pytest' it says 'no module named pytest'","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"try creating a virtual environment like so while inside your lab02 folder gt virtualenv --python python3.6 myenvironment activating it gt source myenvironment/bin/activate installing all packages defined inside the requirements file gt pip3 install -r requirements.txt edit please read new instructions","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"it works now thank you","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"i can't run pytest. it shows bash pytest command not found. i downloaded the packages also.","answers":[{"text":"please read https //webcms3.cse.unsw.edu.au/comp1531/18s2/foru...","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"when i run pytest or test_count.py i get this error test_count.py unhandled exception occurred while testing test_count traceback most recent call last file /usr/lib/python2.7/dist-packages/logilab/common/pytest.py line 447 in testfile options self.options outstream sys.stderr file /usr/lib/python2.7/dist-packages/logilab/common/pytest.py line 763 in __init__ testloader nonstricttestloader file /usr/lib/python2.7/unittest/main.py line 77 in __init__ self.module __import__ module file test_count.py line 16 syntaxerror non-ascii character ' xe2' in file test_count.py on line 16 but no encoding declared see http //python.org/dev/peps/pep-0263/ for details the program seems to work i'm just not sure why the test program throws an error any help would be much apprecaited","answers":[{"text":"hi brendan please make sure that you are using python 3.6 currently you are using python 2.7 . if you have not installed python 3.6 please install it if you do have it installed and if it is throwing the same error please try running the pytest by python3 -m pytest","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i have python 3.6 installed but when i run python3 -m pytest i get /usr/bin/python3.6 no module named pytest do i need use python3 to install pytest thanks for your reply","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"yup in that case try 'pip3 install pytest' to download pytest for python 3.6","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"it then runs the tests as python 3.5.2 and crashes when it sees the f' as you know is only a feature of 3.6 is there a way i can force it to run as python 3.6 and not 3.5.2 i've tried python3.6 -m pytest","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"i'm confused as to what the error is in my count_char_ordered","answers":[{"text":"hi krittika the first error says that your program printed out w 1 r 1 ... etc. whereas the expected output is l 3 o 2 ... etc. count_char_ordered should print out the characters in the descending order of counts but your function doesn't seem to do this correctly. so please try to understand the current behaviour of your program by testing the function manually with user input. for the second error it seems like you haven't stored any new answers to fib_dict the error says that fib_dict 4 did not work because it doesn't have any value associated with the key '4' yet. to resolve this issue try to consider two cases 1 when your fib_dict does not contain the key 'num' and 2 when your fib_dict does contain the key i.e. when it already has the answer to fib_sequence num . in the first case you should compute the value of fibonacci number using recursion and store that value into fib_dict so that you won't have to compute it again later. in the second case you should simply return the value stored in fib_dict corresponding to 'num' you already have implemented this part . please let me know if you are still having issues also there are previous forum questions amp answers on this - so may be refer to those as well . cheers d","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi guys getting the following errors for all three count.py exercises when i run the pytests please help. thanks","answers":[{"text":"hi jack please try installing the pytest mocker used in the autotest again with 'pip3 install pytest-mock' within your virutal environment.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"for count.py i have several questions 1. which final output type is needed for pytest dictionary set or list 2. need i write print command inside each function 3. i can print what is needed when tested manually since i added print command in my code but i can't pass pytest the error is below need help","answers":[{"text":"hi ziwei as described in the main announcement for the output you must print each character in a separate line. and each line should contain the character and its count separated by a single space. please refer to the announcement for the example output. so instead of returning anything your function is expected to print the results. and the error above is occurring because your code only printed a single line of output whereas the test expects exactly 13 lines. this issue should be resolved as well if you follow the output format explained above.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thanks for the reply d so is that mean i need to add something like print command to print out the outputs like 13 lines","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"yup that's right. try 'print char count ' where 'char' is a variable representing the character and 'count' is the variable representing how many times the character has appeared in the text.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"it works and pass the test thank you very much d","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"i'm not sure what this error means. any help appreciated","answers":[{"text":"hi ravija please try 'pip3 install pytest-mock' and try to run the pytest again. it seems like pytest-mock wasn't installed correctly.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thanks so much it works now","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"for some odd reason the assert tests in pytest for count.py are picking up different output compared to output produced by python when run manually. particularly the letter count for every letter seems to be doubled. it works fine when run manually but the asserts keep picking up incorrect output. can someone please advice.","answers":[{"text":"hi farhan could you please include a screenshot of the outputs so that i can figure out what the actual issue may be thanks","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"the first image shows output when i run my program manually. the second image shows the diff output picked up by pytest. the left set which i believe is my output is different from the output from the first image.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hm... okay here's my guess. are you by any chance calling the 'count_char' function anywhere inside your count.py this could be the cause of the issue if you are not initialising your counting dictionary at the start of the function. this would mean that when pytest is executed your count.py would be loaded and the function would be called on loading setting the counts of the characters to be what they should be but when the pytest actually calls the function for testing you will be incrementing the counts from already existing ones and hence the reason for the double count. so to solve this please simply remove any function calls within count.py and please make sure that you are initialising your counting dictionary at the start of each function call dict_name however if my guess was wrong quite likely please either send me a copy of your code via email or push your current work to github so i may inspect it further. d cheers ian.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hi park yes it is as you suspected. i've been initialising my dictionary outside my function all this time this was pointed out to me by my tutor as i had my lab today so i guess i owe both of you. we're all good now. thanks for taking your time with this","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"count_char_ordered pytest problem my program ranked them correctly according to the times that char appears but when it comes to the chars that appear the same times my order is different from the pytest's outcome and so i cant pass it.","answers":[{"text":"hi xiang please try replacing your test_count.py file with the file provided in 'more robust test for count.py' listed in the labs section for week 2 if you are having issues with different ordering mechanism used by the pytest. please let me know if you are still experiencing issues. cheers ian","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"it works cheers","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"pytest not running past session starting running in vlab from my mac new stuck on test_fib.py indefinitely as pictured below. i have triple checked all my functions and they all run as they should and downloaded the more robust test file for count.py. not sure why this is happening.","answers":[{"text":"hi yutian it is most likely that your implementation of fibonacci is not efficient enough. please try to utilise the given dict fib_dict in order to avoid re-computing the same fibonacci number when the function is called several times with the same parameter. for more explanation please refer to previous forum question amp answers because this has been addressed numerous time already. but if you are still having issues please let me know. d cheers ian","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"does anyone know how to install pytest on mac","answers":[{"text":"yup just try 'pip3 install pytest' assuming that you have pip3 installed . but for the lab02 you should try to follow the instructions for installing pytest and other dependencies on virtual environment pip3 install -r requirements.txt .","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"i'm getting an error on test_count.py in the pytest program lab02/lib/python3.5/site-packages/py/_path/local.py 668 in pyimport __import__ modname e file /mnt/c/users/ellen/cs1531-lab02/test_count.py line 83 e o_buffer f' char count n' e e syntaxerror invalid syntax in count.py i am printing the output as a string one line at a time and the output looks correct if i test manually. i'm not sure if this is because of something my output is causing having a bit of trouble with debugging it. any suggestions","answers":[{"text":"if anyone else is stuck on this after installing python 3.6 i had to run virtualenv lab02 -p python3.6 to get the virtual env to set up with 3.6 otherwise it still defaulted to python3.5","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hi ellen for this course you are required to use python version 3.6 exactly. currently you are using python3.5 - which does not support the f'...' feature utilised in the pytest file. so please make sure that you have installed python v3.6 not python 3.7 either because it does have some features not in 3.6 . please let me know if you are still having issues after installing python 3.6 d cheers ian.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hi ian i'm now getting another error fixture mocker not found. the venv is in python 3.6. i have run through the entire setup process again to make sure i did everything right.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hi ellen please try to install pytest-mock again within the virtual environment i believe the autotest is trying to use an outdated version of a library gt gt pip3 install pytest-mock please let me know if you still have any issues after installing it. d","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thanks it worked d","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"ok thanks ian","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"problem for home device setting when i run it shows the path /usr/bin/python3 from --python /usr/bin/python3 does not exist so i run virtualenv --python /usr/bin/python venv it works fine but when i run pytest it shows please help thank you","answers":[{"text":"hi chenghe the error is occurring because the f'...' syntax newly introduced in python v3.6. please make sure that you are using python3.6 for this course not 3.5 as you have at the moment and not v3.7 either because it also contains some features not provided in 3.6 . please let me know if you are still having issues after installing it. d","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thanks for your help i have done this lab in school computer.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"for count.py does the order letters with the same count that are printed out matter here's an example of what my program prints using helloworld this is the example written in the lab if so what pattern should characters of the same count follow edit pytest keeps on crashing when i run the test for fibonacci i have already included the if statement not sure what i'm doing wrong there...","answers":[{"text":"hi angela yes you are right you may print out characters with the same count in any order - except the pytest does not account for it - so i have put up a more flexible and proper test on the labs page please copy and replace your test_count with the new one. or instead you can just ask your tutor to check the outputs manually if you prefer that option. actually pytest expects the character that appeared first in the text to come before the other character in the results if they have the same count - so you could try implementing your code this way . also for fibonacci it is probably crashing because you forgot to utilise the fib_dict dictionary - without this the program will be very inefficient and will not be able to handle large inputs such as 100 or 1000. try to think of fib_dict as a memo for storing question-answer pairs. for example fib_dict 0 0 1 1 2 1 tell us that we already know the answer for the questions fib_sequence 0 fib_sequence 1 and fib_sequence 2 - which are 0 1 1 respectively. so to optimise your function you can do the following 1. if you already know the answer to fib_sequence num the just return the answer stored in fib_dict 2. otherwise compute the answer by recursion answer fib_sequence ... fib_sequence ... and store that answer in fib_dict fib_dict ... ... - so that you won't have to compute it again - and return that answer. in this way if you already have computed the answer for a question then you do not have to compute it again and only have to return the answer we have stored in fib_dict. this will improve the performance of your function dramatically. the ...'s are left for you to fill out d","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thanks so much for the detailed response","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"quick question - when running the tests in the virtual environment the asserts are output as comparisons between 2 sets left and right . which set represents my program output left or right also i think the asserts output different results compared to whats output when run manually. please advice.","answers":[{"text":"hi farhan for this pytest the ones on the left represents your output the ones on the right are the expected. regarding the second question could you please attach some screenshots of the outputs both from the 'asserts' and from manual running i am not so sure by just reading the words but my guess is that you have things like ' n' in the assert outputs - but these just denote a newline in your output. please let me know if if you think it's something else. d","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"traceback most recent call last file count.py line 335 in lt module gt count_char text1 file count.py line 283 in count_char print u2019 letter_list ' u2019' unicodeencodeerror 'latin-1' codec can't encode character ' u2019' in position 0 ordinal not in range 256 -----python won't recognise ' character. please advice.","answers":[{"text":"hi farhan. yup that is a mistake on my part - which is happening only to some students for some reason please try wrapping the string for text1 with double quotation marks instead of single-quotes ' ' and re-write the single-quote in ... won't ... by removing it and adding it back using your keyboard not copy-paste . so change ' i felt happy because i saw the others were happy and because i knew i should feel happy but i wasn t really happy ' to i felt happy because i saw the others were happy and because i knew i should feel happy but i wasn't really happy thanks ian","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"runtimeerror maximum recursion depth exceeded is the error i keep getting when trying to run fibonacci.py could someone please help me","answers":[{"text":"note that python will limit how deep your recursion can go to prevent unlimited recursion which is a big problem in itself. so to calculate fibonacci for very large numbers it is wise to utilise the dictionary in some way to reduce the amount of computations required for these very large numbers.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i think that may mean your function can't stop recursing meaning the condition for stopping your function from recursion isn't met. i'm not sure if what i'm doing is right as pytest doesn't work for fibonacci for me but i guess a hint is to copy the formula they gave us in the comments of the file","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"the requirements of count.py are not clear enough for example spaces and commas are not counted based on the output example from https //webcms3.cse.unsw.edu.au/comp1531/18s2/reso... . however spaces and commas are counted in test_count.py . should we return a list dictionary or just print the results from our function i keep getting errors from pytest for count.py but it works fine manually.","answers":[{"text":"hi matthew i am really sorry about the confusion - i believe there was some miscommunication among the admins. the correct example input amp output are do count_char_ordered helloworld output l 3 o 2 h 1 e 1 w 1 r 1 d 1 1 space and commas should be counted as well basically every character should be counted if there are any. and you shouldn't just return the dictionary but instead print the results as shown by the example output every character must be printed in a separate line along with its count. please let me know if you continue to have issues with the exercise. regards ian.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"same issue here. it works fine manually but pytest keeps complaining. can someone please advice.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i'm not sure what your issue is but one thing you have to do it print every item in your dictionary on a new line.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hi alex yeah my code updates my dictionary and then proceeds to print every dictionary item on a new line with the appropriate count. i can't seem to figure out where my output is going wrong. i suspect that maybe it is the order in which the letters are printed that might be causing the asserts to fail. however for the first exercise order doesn't need to accounted for so i'm not really sure.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"use pytest -vv to see what is actually different from the two outputs.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"oserror reading from stdin while output is captured are we supposed to write code to accept user input in fibonacci.py when i run pytest with code to accept user input i get the above error. when i run pytest without it runs fine.","answers":[{"text":"the issue is indeed due to your fibonacci.py asking for a user input when the pytests are running. however there is a way to keep that input-reading code while letting the test work. try placing your input-reading code under this if statement in fibonacci.py if __name__ '__main__' read input print this means that only run the body of the code under the if statement only when fibonacci.py file is directly executed python3 fibonacci.py - otherwise this part of the code would not run and hence wouldn't interfere with pytest either. d","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i am facing the same issue. it works fine when i run it manually. however pytest gives me the same error as above.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"are we permitted to use string methods for this weeks exercises","answers":[{"text":"yup yes you are d","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi what is the output format for count_char count_char_insensitive and count_char_ordered also when i run pytest i get this fixture 'mocker' not found message. what does it mean thanks","answers":[{"text":"hi igansius for count.py exercises you should print information about each character in a separate line and the information about a character should be the character followed by its count with a space in between . so if you have five h's three e's and ten a's a possible output could be h 5 e 3 a 10 of course for count_char_ordered the output should be ordered by the character count. also if you are getting a message regarding the mocker please make sure that you have installed all the dependencies in the requirements.txt as shown in the lab instructions . if you do not think that this is the issue please let me know. cheers ian","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"how do we run individual test on our files please advice. thanks","answers":[{"text":"hi farhan please try 'pytest lt test file name gt ' e.g. pytest test_count.py to test your solutions. if that does not work sometimes it doesn't please try 'python3 -m pytest lt test file name gt ' instead. d","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi when i run each test individually no issues come up however when i run pytest it hangs at test_fib.py also how are they supposed to show up when the tests are passed with pytest thanks","answers":[{"text":"hi sophie you may implement the function using binet's formula as an extension woohoo but for this lab exercise you must use recursion to complete the lab. furthermore binet's formula may not actually be faster try it yourself unless further optimisations are made. about the input/print bit yes the pytest would crash normally due to the input function being called while the test is running. however there is a way to keep the input/print bits in the code while not interrupting the pytest. try wrapping your input/print bits under the following if statement if __name__ '__main__' read input compute fib print output it means you should only run the block of code under the if statement only if the file was executed directly from the terminal and not indirectly through other files e.g. pytests . d","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hi sophie although i cannot say for sure this is a common problem that occurs with the exercise when the students forget to optimise the algorithm using the dictionary 'fib_dict' provided appropriately. please be warned that the function will behave very slowly without using it - and thus the test will take forever to run waiting for your function to complete it could actually take more than few trillion years . here's a little hint if you follow the execution of fib_sequence 100 you will realise that calling fib_sequence 100 will call fib_sequence 99 and fib_sequence 98 . but when fib_sequence 99 is called it will call fib_sequence 98 too so in fact fib_sequence 98 will be computed twice in a naive implementation - hence inefficiency occurs. this kind of redundant computation occurs even more frantically as you continue to follow down the execution of fib_sequence 100 e.g. fib_sequence 2 will be called 135301852344706746049 times in total . so please have a think about how you could avoid repeating same computations using 'fib_dict'. by the way for your interest the name of this technique is called 'memoisation'. hope this helped. d","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"hi su just read up on memoisation that helped a lot. thanks for the detailed explanation","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"error information requested url /cgi-bin/action-cgiwrap/ cs1531/github/run.cgi/import query string error status 500 error notes malformed header from script. bad header file /tmp_amd/kamen/export/ /usr/local/apache/cgi-bin/action-cgiwrap request protocol http/1.1 server name cgi.cse.unsw.edu.au server port 443","answers":[{"text":"hi yuqin sorry the app was down for a while it should be working now. d","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"does this happened because i'm using python3.7 not 3.5 or because i'm working under win10","answers":[{"text":"hi jiayi it seems like to me that you do not have 'python3' installed or may be you installed it under a different name 'python' . usually 'python' denotes python v2. and python3 denotes python v3. - so please make sure that you have the correct version installed. if you actually do have the correction version but it is somehow installed under the name 'python' you may edit the test_python.sh file to use 'python' instead of 'python3'. please let me know if you are still having troubles or the above did not solve the issues. d","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hi if doing the lab 01 was a mess and kinda confusing the first time is there a way we can redo the lab possibly deleting the whole file and redownloading thanks","answers":[{"text":"yes there is a replace feature implemented. go to the page in which you had setup labs and assignments.the link for this is https //cgi.cse.unsw.edu.au/ cs1531/github/run.cgi/login this link is also found on the lab01 setup. go to the lab page and select lab01. there will be a replace button which will delete your imported repo on github and re-import a fresh one.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"hey i have tried several times to merge master and my master branch but the python file i upload is still in my new branch instead of master so is it getting me any trouble for showing that i have submitted before due","answers":[{"text":"hi jiayi please try the following 1. first figure out which branch on your local repository has the python files you would like to push to github 2. if it is not on the master branch go to the master branch git checkout master and then merge the other branch into master git merge lt other branch name gt 3. git add commit push now the finished python files should show up in the master branch on github. please try to get the changes on the master branch as asked - it's a good practice for learning git. cheers ian","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"an error message pops up whenever i try to push a new branch to github did i miss a step and what am i doing wrong all i did before was create the branch and moved inside the branch before trying to push it. ---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- $ git push -u origin python exercises error src refspec python does not match any. error src refspec exercises does not match any. error failed to push some refs to ' https //github.com/r0ckyr0ad/cs1531-lab01.git '","answers":[{"text":"hi matthew if you have a whitespace in the branch name you should enclose the name between a pair of double quotes to indicate that the two words are in fact one 'thing'. please try git push -u origin python exercises instead if your branch name is indeed python exercises . cheers ian","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"is there a give command that we have to use or do we just show our tutor","answers":[{"text":"hi alex in this course there will be minimal use of give perhaps except for the assignments - instead please make sure to push your work to the remote repository on github to the master branch by the upcoming sunday 11.59pm. then during the first hour of the next week's lab you may show your work to your tutor and get it marked off. cheers ian d","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"i got a error code 500 problem when i tried to import the files of lab01 idk wot to do with it. i'm worried about the time.","answers":[{"text":"our webapp had some issues for a short period. the webapp is up and running again. please try now.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"i'm unable to push because updates were rejected because the tip of your current branch is behind its remote counterpart . here's the full error message i have no clue what i'm doing wrong help would be greatly appreciated. i'm using a public repo as my education account still hasn't been approved.","answers":[{"text":"if you read the hints the messages would suggest that remotely on github the branch is ahead of your local machine's branch. what you would need to do is git pull to update your local machine branch to get it up to date before pushing any changes local- gt remote. it is honestly recommended to regularly pull to keep up-to-date with remote. this becomes very important in your future group project.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thanks. sorry if this is stupid but i'm not sure how to specify the branch as simply typing git pull doesn't work . i tried git pull origin master after checking the branches via git branch but that doesn't work either","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"what set of commands did you use to setup your public repository on your local machine did you initialise a new repo locally or push an existing repo.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i typed in git init and then git remote add origin ssh url .","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"you may have forgotten to do gt git push -u origin master on setup which would have linked your local to remote.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thank you so much","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"my education pack didn't come through so i tried to set up my own git repository. when i tried however it came up with this error message im not sure what to do exactly to fix this.","answers":[{"text":"hi ewan you must first turn your directory/folder into a git repository using 'git init' before you can do 'git remote add ...' - just as angla has said thank you angela . please try it and please let me know if it still does not solve the problem. d","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"try typing git init before you type git remote add .... it fixed the problem for me but idk if that's what we're supposed to do","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"my github education discount pack was rejected and i'm unsure if i'm entering my details correctly or not so i clicked on 'student' and 'individual account'. then for name i entered my full name that appears on my student id. i then used my zid student.unsw.edu.au account that has been verified. school name unsw graduation year 2018 my reason was copied and pasted i will use github to work on group projects and as the version control tool for my coursework.","answers":[{"text":"hi cattleya the lab01 faq page has been released so please have a look at it and see if you can resolve your issues. if you are still having issues after following the faq page or if you are not too sure on how to follow the instructions listed please let me know. cheers ian","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i got the same problem and i've got replied from github staff. i'm not so sure but it may be a quick solution","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"try uploading your id card or your academic transcript like it says in the box i think a real person will check it and then give you the educational discount. let me know if it works.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i used a photo of my id card and the request was accepted. thank you for all the suggestions and help.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"make sure your graduation year is correct. if it is 2018 then you will be out of unsw by the end of 2018 and into the workforce implying that you are in your final year of study . also i think your email should be zid ad.unsw.edu.au or zid cse.unsw.edu.au rather than zid student.unsw.edu.au. although i'm not sure myself as i got my education pack a long time ago. and as always make sure your details are correct. but other than that i can't really help i suggest asking your tutor or maybe aarthi today during the lecture break.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i had the same thing happen to me not sure what to do.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"do we need to use our github username on name field during github edu pack application i put my real name and i got rejected twice with my unsw.edu.au and student.unsw.edu.au email .","answers":[{"text":"thank you kevin for sharing your great solution to the issue","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i think it is your real name. did you get some sort of email saying that github is trying to verify you and that they need a picture of your academic transcript or student id card","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"nevermind i already got my pack. i had to verify using cse.unsw.edu.au email to be approved","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"my github education account has been denied 3 times for some reason. my last two requests got denied instantly i received a disapproving email straight after submitting my application . i applied with my real name and student email zid student.unsw.edu.au do i also need to upload student affiliation thanks","answers":[{"text":"hi shangjie the faq page has been released now - please go an have a look at possible ways to resolve your issue. however if you still cannot resolve your issue after going through the faq please let us know asa . thanks ian","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"use zid cse.unsw.edu.au email refer to thread https //webcms3.cse.unsw.edu.au/comp1531/18s2/foru... if your lab is coming up or has already past just use a public repo and make it private later.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"i have committed and pushed the files but how could i check whether it is submitted successfully ps i checked the comp lab check it shows that i have not submitted week01 lab exercise. however i pushed them yesterday.","answers":[{"text":"hi jiahao please kindly note that we are not using give for the lab submissions in this course - instead you only need to push your work to github by the upcoming sunday 11.59pm. then in the first hours of next week's lab you may show your work to your tutor and get it marked off - so no need to use give and no need to check on give - just github. cheers ian","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"am i correct in saying the that you committed and pushed the files onto your repo if that is the case then you wouldn't have submitted. usually you can submit using the give command on the terminal. i'm not so sure what you mean by submitted successfully as far as i am aware you have to show your tutor that you have done the work then he/she will give you a grade. i didn't even know that there is a comp lab check mind if you give out the link because i can't find it.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"i did not finish it in the lab because i just got the student pack a few minutes before the lab ended. here is the link of comp lab check https //cgi.cse.unsw.edu.au/ give/code/login.php app / give/student/sturec.php amp debug abort/get_authuser .","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"thanks for the link yes this does look familiar. check this with your tutor but i think you have to show your tutor the work that you have done and then he will be the one who submits a mark out of 10 for your lab which you can later see.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"my lab is this afternoon but i haven't got my github education account approved does it mean i won't be able to do the lab","answers":[{"text":"it's only the lab import that cannot be done. you should still be able to do the python exercises locally you could also just use a public repo for the moment and test all the git commands. once github education is approved then you could do import lab01 code and push your changes to the repo.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"oh ok it's not too bad then. btw is there any help session this week thanks","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"there are consultations every week from 2.30 to 4 room 203 level 2 k17 every thursday.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"my tutor told me i should leave after reading through the lab thoroughly as you can't really access the labs tab of https //cgi.cse.unsw.edu.au/ cs1531/github/run.cgi/ without an education account","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"oh i guess you can just create a public repo for now and follow the lab instructions instead of actually click and go into the lab page","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"some people have had their github education discount approved after five minutes and for others including me it's taking much longer. is there anything i could potentially be doing wrong that is delaying the process or is the approval time variation random and i should just wait a few more days","answers":[{"text":"the approval time-period is really random generally it comes through within 48 hours. if it has been more than 72 hours the i suggest that you reapply. but meanwhile you can do the python exercises locally and use a public repo and test the various git features.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"okay thank you","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"why does the github authorisation for the 1531 organisation require read and write access as well as delete access i have multiple private forked repositories that are to be maintained as secret where i work and i can't allow outside access to these as per nda's and various other sources of legal mumbo jumbo. i have already previous used my unsw email to give me the 'student pack' under my main account and so it is not as easy as just making another account for unsw usage my biggest concern is that i have a lab tomorrow so sorry for this inconvenience . edit it has come to my attention that from our side we can limit the scope i.e. https //github.com/login/oauth/authorize client_id... which limits it to only public data is that acceptable edit 2 i have resolved the problem by creating an account primarily for uni purposes which can also use the student pack under the alias i hope this is sufficient .","answers":[{"text":"hi braedon thank you so much for raising your sincere concerns about the 1531's oauthapp the github app and helping us improve the learning experience for the students of comp1531. also we really appreciate your sharing with us about how you resolved the problem. but to eliminate such privacy concerns for other and future students we have decided to modify the app to limit its access levels. please kindly note that currently no staffs of comp1531 has read/write access to your repos except for those repos created under the organisation. however once again we will further investigate the problem to definitely ensure that no breach of privacy could ever occur through the app. if you have any other concerns or issues please let us know d thanks ian park","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"we will only need the delete scope if you want full functionality of the class manager. occasionally there will be times where students will need to delete their working repo and refork the lab to start fresh. we wish to make it seamless for students new to git and github. feel free to limit the scope if you are comfortable with github and won't be needing this feature also feel free to make another account specifically for unsw if you find that appropriate as many others have done so to not mix up repos.","theta":1,"count":0},{"text":"can i second this - i also have projects i host that i can't share under such a broad agreement. edit re limiting scope i don't even think i could do that because i don't have transparency on whether that actually changes the content of the oauth request and it's kind of hacky at best.","theta":1,"count":0}]},{"question":"so the tutorial asks to make a new repository and set it to private. setting to private costs money and i am poor. can i keep it public","answers":[{"text":"one of the instructions in the lab setup tasks asks you to request for github education account this will give you unlimited private repositories","theta":1,"count":0}]}]}